In this notebook, you're looking at different measures of similarity and distance.
在此 notebook 中 你将学习不同的相似性和距离衡量方法
This will be more of a test on the ability to move math to code than anything else.
这个 notebook 主要检测从数学概念到代码的转换能力
Being able to move from math to code and vice versa,
在数学概念和代码之间相互转换
is a really useful skill as you want to gain
是一项很重要的技能
more flexibility in creating models of your own.
使你能够更加灵活地创建自己的模型
Let's get started and look at a few of the most popular techniques.
下面我们将学习几种最热门的技巧
At the top here, you can see that we'll be looking at three measures of similarity;
在顶部 我列出了我们将学习的三种相似性衡量方法
one is the Pearson's correlation coefficient,
一个是皮尔逊相关系数
another is the Spearman's correlation coefficient,
另一个是斯皮尔曼相关系数
and the third is Kendall's Tau.
第三个是 Kendall's Tau 相关系数
Pearson's correlation coefficient has an equation that looks like this.
皮尔逊相关系数的方程是这样的
So, our first task is to essentially calculate
第一项任务是
the Pearson's correlation coefficient for any two arrays.
计算任何两个数组的皮尔逊相关系数
The first thing that I wanted to do,
首先
was just calculate the mean for each observation for each individual array.
我需要计算每个观察量或每个数组的均值
So, I'm going to create,
我将创建
what I'll call mean X and mean Y.
mean_x 和 mean_y
Essentially, we can get this by taking the sum of X divided by the length of X.
等于 x 的和除以 x 的长度
So, I'm just following this equation here saying,
也就是这个公式
the mean for X is going to be this and we could
x 的均值将等于这个
also make a separate function for this is we wanted to.
也可以创建单独的函数
So, now we have the mean for both of those things,
算出两个数组的均值后
and then essentially what we want to do is get these parts.
下面需要计算这些部分
So, you'll see that this part shows up over and over again throughout
这部分在方程里出现了多次
the equation where we're taking Y minus Y bar,
也就是 y -(y
Y minus Y bar, X minus X bar.
和 x - (x
So, we can do that by essentially taking if these X's and Y's are arrays,
如果 x 和 y 是数组
we can just take the difference between that array and the mean.
计算方法是用数组减去均值
Let's call it X diffs.
称为 x_diffs
We'll call this Y diffs and it's going to be equal to the same thing.
这个称为 y_diffs 计算方法一样
We could set this up the same way we did up there.
设置方法和上面一样
Say Y diffs part.
y_diffs...
Let's just take this part.
将这部分剪切到这里
Great.
Great
Cool. So, now that we have those differences,
好的算出这些差值后
we can compute out the rest of this.
我们可以计算剩余部分了
So, what we want to do is in this top part for each element in this array,
在分子中 对于这个数组里的每个元素
we want to multiply it by
我们都会将该元素
that same index of that element in the Y diffs array and then essentially,
与 y_diffs 数组中相同索引处的元素相乘
we just want to sum them together.
然后求和
So, that will give us this numerator part up here.
这就是分子部分的计算方法
So, if we take np sum of X diffs.
输入 np.sum(x_diffs)
So, that's essentially this whole thing,
对应的是这一部分
and we just want to multiply that by Y diffs. All right.
乘以 y_diffs好的
Then, this part summing them all up.
然后对它们求和
Then, we want to take X diffs squared and,
接着求 x_diffs 的平方
then basically we want to sum that up.
然后求和
We want to take the square root.
再求平方根
So, that's giving us this part over here and we want to do
对应的是这部分
the same thing with this part over here but with the Y portion.
这部分也一样 不过替换成 y
All right. So, I'm just going to make sure that we are, not that it should matter.
好的我将确保...这并不重要
So, we're going to take this np sum of these two things together,
对这两个运行 np.sum()
and we're going to divide it by essentially squaring
分母的计算方法是
these things and then summing them all
对这些项求平方和
together and then taking the square root and then doing that same thing for the Y's.
接着求平方根 然后对 y 进行相同的计算
So, this should give us our correlation coefficient which we can return back.
这就是我们要返回的相关系数
Then, the cell is to test,
下面是测试单元格
and it looks like we pass all the tests.
我们通过了所有测试
So, now that you've computed Pearson's correlation coefficient,
计算了皮尔逊相关系数后
we can answer a few questions about it.
我们来回答几个问题
So, if when X increases,
如果 x 增大 y 也增大
Y also increases, Pearson's correlation will always be one.
那么皮尔逊相关系数始终为 1
So, that's actually not true.
这句话不对
So, you can imagine things that are increasing but not in a line.
有时候会增大 但不是一条直线
So, Pearson's correlation coefficient always is defined by a line,
皮尔逊相关系数始终由一条线定义
and if they increase by like a quadratic,
如果按照二项式关系增大
this statement is true.
这个表述就正确
But Pearson's correlation will not be one.
但是皮尔逊相关系数并非始终为 1
If when X increases by one,
如果当 x 增加 1 时 y 始终增加 3
Y always increases by three, the correlation will be one.
那么相关系数为 1
So, that's actually a true statement.
这句话实际上正确
Great. So, that one's true.
Great.所以这句话正确
That's essentially a line. So, X increases by one,
这是一条线当 x 增加 1 时
Y increases by three.
y 增加 3
X increases by one,
当 x 增加 1 时 y 增加 3
Y increases by three and that's going to be a true statement.
这句话是正确的
So similarly, if X increases by one,
同理 如果 x 增加 1
Y always decreases by five,
y 始终减 5
this will always be a negative one.
那么皮尔逊系数将为 -1
That's actually a true statement as well.
这句话也正确
So, that's another line.
这是另一条线
That'll create another line.
将创建另一条线
Then, if when X increases by one,
如果 x 增加 1
Y increases by three times X.
y 增加 3x
That's no longer a line.
这不再是直线
So, this falls into one of the scenarios up here that would be false.
属于这里的其中一种情形
So, that would actually be a false statement.
这句话不正确
All right. So, B. That's right.
好的答案是 b
There's a little explanation there.
下面解释了原因